Narrator: 1
Sheryl and Dharmesh
Emily: But soon after the couple got married in 1992,
they began to realize their food differences were too big to be fixed by a spoon.
Dharmesh was training to be a dentist whilst Sheryl stayed at home,
so she did all the cooking.
Sheryl: My simple, you know, chicken and potatoes, basic foods and – that was interesting,
because he would put masala and anything hot and spicy on top of it that he could find.
I felt a little bit insulted, like, you know,
you can understand cultural differences in your head,
but in your heart it’s, it’s hard to accept.
I felt, like, ‘Wow, he doesn’t like my cooking!’
Emily: And, Dharmesh, what were you thinking at the time?
Were you enjoying this food that Sheryl was making? Be honest.
Dharmesh: Er, it was very bland, honestly.
Narrator: 2
Rebecca and Saj
Rebecca: When I see anyone eat meat, but in particular Saj,
it’s a thing that’s quite hard to describe to people who aren’t vegan.
It’s not just nauseating and kind of a little bit gross,
it’s also something, kind of, profoundly hurtful,
so it’s even worse watching someone that you love doing that
and I think that’s where the tolerance has to come from.
Saj: My favourite meaty meal is a chicken teriyaki.
Like, that’s the thing that I really hanker for.
So, if I’m finishing work, I walk past this Japanese restaurant
and they’ve got just this most amazing chicken teriyaki.
Emily: Do you tell Rebecca about it when you get home?
Saj: Um, no I – I usually don’t.
Just depends on how brave I’m feeling.